Just a moment ago, I made some pretty big claims by saying that
たった今、Claudeはツールを非常にうまく活用できると言って、かなりの大胆な発言をしました。
Claude was an expert at making use of tools. And
そして、Claudeのコードは簡単に拡張可能だと言いました。当然、
that Claude code was easily extensible. Naturally,
少し懐疑的になるかもしれませんが、いくつか
you might be a little skeptical, so I'd like to give you a few
簡単なデモンストレーションをしたいと思います。このテーブルには、
quick demonstrations. On this table are the
Claudeのコードで利用できるデフォルトのツールがあります。
default tools that are available in Claude code. It
Claudeのコードで利用できるデフォルトのツールがここにあります。
has all the abilities you would expect, like reading files,
ファイルの読み取り、ファイルの書き込み、コマンドの実行など、期待されるすべての機能があります。
writing files, running commands, and so on. I'm
Claudeのコードを使用したタスクをいくつかご紹介します。
going to show you a couple of tasks completed using
Claude Codeを使用して完了したタスクをいくつかご紹介します。
Claude Code. And in each case, it will use
そして、各ケースでは、これらの
this set of tools in rather intelligent ways. And
ツールのセットを非常にインテリジェントな方法で使用します。そして、
in at least one task, I'll even give Claude an
少なくとも1つのタスクでは、Claudeに
additional new set of tools to make use of.
追加の新しいツールのセットを使ってもらいます。
Not only will this process give you a good idea of what Claude
このプロセスにより、Claudeのコードが
code can do right out of the box, but hopefully
すぐに何ができるかの良いアイデアが得られるだけでなく、
you will also see how easily you can extend Claude
Claudeのコードにどのように簡単に
code with more functionality. Here's my
さらに機能を追加できるかも理解できるはずです。
first task for Claude code. I'm going to ask it to find
これが、Claudeコードの最初のタスクです。
and optimize performance issues in the chalk library.
チョークライブラリのパフォーマンスの問題を見つけて最適化するように依頼します。
In case you're not familiar with it, chalk is a JavaScript package.
ご存じない方のために説明すると、チョークはJavaScriptパッケージです。
Here's the documentation for it. Now this is a very
これがそのドキュメントです。さて、これは非常に
small library that has one very simple purpose.
小さなライブラリで、1つの非常に簡単な目的があります。
All it does is print out text in nicely formatted
やっていることは、テキストをきれいにフォーマットされた
colors, so like exactly as you see in this example screenshot
色で出力することです。ここでは、この例のスクリーンショットでご覧になれるように。
right here. So you can give the text colors or backgrounds
ここでご覧になれるとおりです。テキストに色や背景を付けたり、
and formatting, all that kind of stuff. Now, this
フォーマットしたり、そのようなことができます。さて、これは
might sound like a really simple and silly package,
非常にシンプルでつまらないパッケージのように聞こえるかもしれませんが、
but here's the thing. It turns out this is actually the fifth
実はこれはJavaScriptエコシステム全体で5番目に
most downloaded package in the entire JavaScript ecosystem.
ダウンロードされているパッケージなのです。
Last week in particular, it had 429
特に先週は、4億2900万回
million downloads. So this package is used
ダウンロードがありました。ですから、このパッケージは
far and wide to put it simply. If
広く使われています。簡単に言えば、
I could find any way to optimize anything inside
このパッケージ内の何かを最適化する方法を見つけられたなら、
this package, well, it would probably be worth the effort.
それはおそらく労力に見合うでしょう。
So I'm going to ask Claude to run the benchmarks, identify
そこでClaudeにベンチマークを実行させ、パフォーマンスの低いケースを特定し、
the worst performing cases, use some profiling tools
プロファイリングツールを使ってそれらのケースがなぜ
to figure out why those cases are running so slowly, and then
それほど遅いのかを突き止め、そして修正するように依頼します。
fix them. We'll then see that Claude is going to use a wide
Claudeがこの問題をインテリジェントに解決するために、さまざまなツールを幅広く使用することになります。
variety of different tools to intelligently tackle this problem.
さまざまなツールをインテリジェントに活用して、この問題を解決します。
It'll form up a 2DList to track its progress,
進捗状況を追跡するために2Dリストを作成し、
execute commands to run the benchmarks, write a file to better
ベンチマークを実行するためのコマンドを実行し、ファイルを書き込み、
zoom in on one particular case, use a CPU
特定のケースに焦点を当てるためにCPU
profiler to understand why that case is running so slowly,
プロファイラを使用して、そのケースがなぜそれほど遅いのかを理解し、
and then implement some improvements. By the end,
そして改善策を実装します。
we'll get a 3.9 times improvement in throughput
最終的には、このライブラリのある特定の操作で
in one particular operation around this library. Here's
スループットが3.9倍向上します。
another example of how well Claude can string together different
これは、Claudeがさまざまなツール呼び出しをどの程度うまく連携させて、
tool calls to complete a rather complex task. I'm
かなり複雑なタスクを完了できるかを示す別の例です。
going to give it a data set inside the CSV file. All
CSVファイルの中にデータセットを渡します。
the data inside of here contains information about different users
この中のすべてのデータには、さまざまなユーザーに関する情報が含まれています。
of a video streaming platform. And I'm going to ask it to
ビデオストリーミングプラットフォームのユーザーの。そして、私はそれに依頼します。
just do a general analysis, maybe identify some causes
一般的な分析を行い、おそらくいくつか原因を特定してほしいです。
of churn on the platform. And I want all this analysis
プラットフォームの解約の原因を特定してほしいです。そして、私はこのすべての分析を
to be done inside of a Jupyter notebook. Here's
Jupyter Notebookの中で行ってほしいです。これが
my data set. I'm then going to ask Claude to run
私のデータセットです。次にClaudeに実行を依頼します。
the analysis and let's see how it does. This is
分析を行って、どのように機能するかを見てみましょう。
a great example of where effective tool use is really
これは、効果的なツールの使用が本当に重要である
important. You see, it's not really enough that
場面の良い例です。Claudeがノートブックにコードを
Claude just writes code into a notebook. Claude can
記述するだけでは十分ではありません。Claudeは
also execute code in different cells and view the results
さまざまなセルでコードを実行し、その実行結果を
of those executions. That means that Claude
表示することもできます。つまり、Claudeは
can take some initial look at the data in the notebook and
ノートブックのデータを最初に確認し、
then customize each successive cell to hone
次に連続する各セルをカスタマイズして、
in on some particular details. Next
特定の詳細に焦点を合わせることができます。次に
up, I'd like to show you an example of a task where I extend Claude
、新しいツールのセットにアクセスさせることで、Claudeコードの
Code's capabilities by giving it access to a new set
機能を拡張するタスクの例を示します。
of tools. I built a small app that will
私は、画面の左側に入力された説明に基づいて
generate UI components based upon some description entered
UIコンポーネントを生成する小さなアプリを構築しました。
on the left side of the screen. The generated component
生成されたコンポーネントは、次に画面の右側に表示されます。
is then displayed on the right side. Now, the app can
このアプリは、見栄えの良いコンポーネントを簡単に生成できますが、
generate good looking components quite easily, but
左側のチャットインターフェースと上部のヘッダーは
the chat interface on the left and the header at the top
あまり見栄えが良くありません。ですから
are not looking so nice. So
、Claudeコードを使ってスタイリングを改善します。
I'm going to use Claude Code to improve the styling. If
チャットインターフェースとヘッダーのスタイリングを修正するように依頼した場合、
I just asked it to fix the styling and the chat interface in the
おそらくうまくいくでしょう。しかし、思い出してください。
header, it would likely do a fine job. But remember,
私の目標は、Claudeコードに
my goal here is to show you how easy it is to
追加の機能を追加するのがどれほど簡単かを示すことです。そこで、このスタイリングタスクとともに、
add additional functionality to Claude Code. So along
さらに、Playwright MCPサーバーと呼ばれる
with this styling task, I'm going to also give Claude Code
ものから提供される新しいツールのセットにClaudeコードに
access to a new set of tools provided by
アクセスさせます。そのPlaywright MCPサーバーについて
something called the Playwright MCP server, which
は、後でもっと詳しく説明します。これらのツールにより、
I'll tell you more about later on. These tools allow
Claudeはブラウザを直接開いて制御できます。
Claude to directly open and control a browser.
Claudeはブラウザを直接開いて制御できるようになります。
So here's what that process looks like in action. I'm
だから、これは実際の動作プロセスです。
going to ask Claude to improve the styling of my app and make
Claudeにアプリのスタイリングを改善するように依頼し、
use of a browser to do so. It'll then open
それを行うためにブラウザを使用させます。
a browser on the right-hand side of the screen. Navigate to my
次に画面の右側にブラウザを開き、
app, it'll take a screenshot to view the current styling,
アプリに移動します。スクリーンショットを撮って現在のスタイリングを確認し、
and then update the styling. We could even ask
そしてスタイリングを更新します。さらにClaudeに
Claude to take another screenshot of the page when
完了時のページのスクリーンショットをもう一度撮らせ、
it was complete and iterate on the design a couple of times
デザインを数回反復させて、本当に良いデザインを
to really get a nice design that really pops. And
得ることができます。すぐに、かなりまともなものができあがりました。
before long, we've got something that actually looks pretty reasonable.
最後に、皆さんに提示したいデモンストレーションがもう一つあります。
There's one last set of demonstrations that I like to give you. Remember
先ほど申し上げたことを思い出してください。Claudeが
what I mentioned a moment ago. Claude's ability to
ツールをうまく活用できる能力こそが、Claudeコードが
utilize tools so well is what will allow Claude code
将来、あなたやあなたのチームと一緒に成長できる
to grow with you and your team in the future. Let
理由となるのです。すぐにその例をお見せしましょう。
me show you an example of that right away. Claude has
ClaudeはGitHubと非常に緊密に連携しています。
a very close integration with GitHub. You can set up Claude
ClaudeコードをGitHubアクション内で実行するように設定でき、
code to run inside of a GitHub action,
プルリクエストの作成や
where it will be executed automatically based upon certain
課題内で直接メンションされた場合など、特定の
events, like creating a pull request or
イベントに基づいて自動的に実行されます。
when directly mentioned inside an issue. When
ClaudeコードがGitHub上で実行されると、
Claude Code runs on GitHub, it not only gets
コードを表示したり実行したりできるだけでなく、
to view and run your code, but it also
コメントの作成、コミットやプルリクエストの作成など、
gets to access a new set of tools for interacting
GitHubとやり取りするための新しいツールのセットにも
with GitHub, like the ability to create comments
アクセスできるようになります。
or create commits or pull requests and so on. You
この連携を使用して、プルリクエストを自動的にレビューできます。
can use this integration to automatically review pull
例を示しましょう。まず、状況を少し設定します。
requests. Let me show you an example. Let me first
AWS上にインフラを構築していると想像してください。
set up a little scenario for you. Let's imagine that we are
そして、すべてのインフラは一連のTerraformファイルで定義されており、
building out some infrastructure on AWS, and all
それらはGitHubにコミットされて保存されています。
of our infrastructure is to find inside of a set of terraform
私たちのすべてのインフラストラクチャはTerraformファイルで定義されているため、
files, which are committed and stored on GitHub.
Claudeコードは、情報がインフラストラクチャをどのように
Because all of our infrastructure is to find inside of terraform
流れているかを非常によく理解しています。
files, Claude Code has a really good idea of how
そして、そのアプリでDynamoDBテーブルがあると想像してください。
information is flowing through our infrastructure.
それらをご存じない方のために言うと、それは通常のデータベーステーブルのようなものです。
And let's imagine that in the SAP, I have a DynamoDB
その中に、ユーザーに関するいくつかの異なる情報を格納しています。
table. If you're not familiar with those, it's kind of like a normal database
たとえば、視聴したプランや
table. Inside there, I'm storing some different information
登録日などです。そして、何らかの理由で
about users, including maybe plans viewed and
視聴したプランと登録日の情報だけを
a registration date. And for maybe some
社内のマーケティングチームと、
reason, we want to share just that plans viewed and
外部のマーケティングチームとも共有したい場合。
registration date information with some internal
つまり、他の会社が私たちがこのバケットに書き込んでいる
marketing team, but also some external
データにアクセスできます。ですから、このバケットに
marketing team as well. So some other company has
書き込まれている情報を常に把握しておくことは非常に重要です。
access to the data that we are writing in this bucket.
夜間に、Lambda関数がテーブルに追加されたすべての
So it's really important for us to always be aware of what information
ユーザーを抽出し、視聴したプランと登録日だけを
is being written into that bucket over time. Nightly,
抽出してS3バケットに保存し、これらの2つのマーケティングチームが
we might have a Lambda function, pull out all the different users
その情報にアクセスできるようにするかもしれません。
that have been added into that table, and then extract just
さて、数か月後に、社内マーケティングチームが
plans for you and the registration date, and store
電子メールもこのS3バケットに保存するように依頼したとします。
that in the S3 bucket so these two marketing teams
そこでLambda関数に入って、ユーザーの電子メールを取得して
can access that information. Now let's
バケットに保存するコードを1行だけ追加したかもしれません。
imagine that months later on, the internal
そして、これが数か月後なので、
marketing team asks us to also store the email
このS3バケットが外部マーケティングパートナーと共有されていることを
inside of this S3 bucket as well. So we might
完全に忘れている可能性があります。ですから
go into the Lambda function and add in just one single line
、今、私たちは個人を特定できる情報（PII）を
of code that takes the user's email and stores it inside
バケットに入れていますが、それは別の会社がアクセスできます。
the bucket. And because this is months later on,
これは大きな禁止事項です。絶対にやってはいけないことです。
we might have completely forgotten that this S3 bucket
しかし同時に、これは発生するエラーであり、
is shared with a external marketing partner. So
S3バケットで何が起こっているかを正確に把握していないと、
now at this point in time, we are putting personally identifiable
見つけるのが難しいです。さて、
information into this bucket, which is accessible
Claudeコードがプルリクエスト内で
by a separate company. This is a big no-no. Definitely
このようなシナリオを非常に簡単にキャッチできることがわかりました。
something we would not want to do. But at the same time, this
特に、すべてのインフラが
is an error that does occur, and it's kind
Terraformファイルで定義されているためです。そこで、簡単な例を示します。
of hard to catch if we don't have a good idea of exactly
先ほどの図で示したプロジェクトを作成しました。Lambda関数にユーザーのメールを追加するプルリクエストを作成しました。
of those terraform files. So here's a quick example.
私が変更したコードはたった一行だけです。
created a pull request to add in the
今、Claudeは私のインフラについて非常に良く理解しています。
user's email inside of the Lambda function. So the only
だから、自動レビューの中で、
line of code that I changed was that right there. I'm saying that
このプルリクエストで行ったすべての変更を見ることができました。
for every user, I want to get their email and add that into
それは私のインフラがどのように機能するかを正確に把握し、
the bucket as well. Now, Claude
私がパートナーにPIIを公開していることを特定できました。
has an excellent idea of my infrastructure. So
だから、ここにデータフローがリストされています。
it was able, inside of a automated review, this
発生した正確なステップ。そして、このバケットが
we're seeing right here, to take a look at all the changes I made
外部パートナーとどのように共有されているかについて、
inside this pull request. It was able to figure out exactly
詳細に説明しています。このような問題をデプロイした後ではなく、
how my infrastructure works, and it was able to identify
開発中に検出することは、GitHub上のClaudeコードの統合を利用する
that I am exposing some PII to
ための素晴らしい利点です。
a partner. So it has listed out the data flow
後で詳細を説明し、このようなフローを
right here, the exact steps that occur. and goes
正確に設定する方法を説明します。
into great detail on how this bucket is shared with a
これで、Claudeコードが何ができるかの良いアイデアが得られたと思います。
external partner. Catching issues like this
ツールを効果的に活用する優れた能力のおかげです。覚えておいてください、
during development instead of after we deploy this
Claudeコードは、柔軟なアシスタントとして考えてください。
change is an amazing benefit to using Claude
カスタマイズ可能で、成長し、時間とともに変化し、
Code's integration on GitHub. I'm going to go into
チームのニーズを満たすことができます。